A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Papers of the Council on Legal Education for Professional Responsibilities, Inc. (CLEPR) FA706
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Papers of the Council on Legal Education for Professional Responsibilities, Inc. (CLEPR)
1968-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA706
16.28 Cubic Feet
In 1982 CLEPR grant files were given to the Ford Foundation Archives by Maximilian W. Kempner, secretary and attorney for CLEPR as well as a member of its Board of Directors and Executive Committee. The Council on Legal Education for Professional Responsibilities, Inc. (CLEPR) was established in 1968 with a $6 million, five-year general support grant from the Ford Foundation. In 1973 CLEPR received a $5 million grant from the Ford Foundation for a second five-year period. CLEPR also received a $290,000 grant from the U.S. Department of Justice Law Enforcement Assistance and Administration program in 1970. The Council was in operation from 1968 until 1981 and was legally dissolved in 1983. CLEPR was successor to the National Council on Legal Clinics and the Council on Education in Professional Responsibilities (both Ford Foundation-supported). Like its predecessors, its goal was to encourage the development of clinical legal education: practical lawyer-client experience for law students while under law school supervision. To this end, CLEPR gave grants to develop clinical projects for law students, to develop teaching and supervisory faculty for the programs and to advocate clinical legal education through publications and conferences.
Scope and Contents
The Council on Legal Education for Professional Responsibility (CLEPR) collection consists of eighteen feet of grant files, 1968-1974. The grant files document the administration of each CLEPR grant--the proposal, terms of approval, interim, annual, and final reports, correspondence between CLEPR and the grantee, and other grant-related material. The papers also include documentation of the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (U.S. Department of Justice) grant to CLEPR for model Prosecutor/Law Student clinical programs. The papers do not contain CLEPR office files, rejected grant proposals, financial records, CLEPR Executive Committee minutes, or grant files created after 1975.
CLEPR awarded grants to law schools in the United States, Canada, and some developing countries to start or improve clinical legal education programs; to individuals for travel and study to improve clinical legal education programs; and to institutions to sponsor conferences. Specific examples include grants to: the University of Tennessee or legal services for lower-income groups with economic and business development needs, Georgetown University for support for the student-staffed public interest law center, Yale University for supervision of student-run Legal Services Organization.
The Ford Foundation Archives holds additional material related to CLEPR. "Enhancing Theory with Practice," by Lance Liebman, is a 1972 evaluation of four years of CLEPR activities (report #002165). The Ford Foundation grant to CLEPR (grant file PA68-894) contains grant correspondence, reports, evaluations and CLEPR newsletters and publications.
This register includes three appendices: an alphabetical list of CLEPR grantees (1968-74), CLEPR grantees 1975-78, and CLEPR Officers and Directors.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Arrangement
Because its "original order" consisted of one or more alphabetical sequences within some years, it was decided to arrange the files chronologically by grant number.
Each CLEPR grant number consists of the last two digits of the year the grant was awarded, a hyphen, and the next available number, e.g. 70-09 was the ninth grant awarded in 1970. Some grant numbers also include a mneumonic letter: J=Justice Department, F=Fellowhip. For example 72-01J was a CLEPR grant to Georgetown University for which CLEPR received grant funds from the Justice Department. In other instances the letter following the grant number, e.g. 71-34b, differentiates two grants with the same number. 71-34 was a grant given to Columbia University; 71-34b was a separate grant also given to Columbia University for a different purpose.
The dates listed for each grant file indicate the duration of the grant.
The grant file format is similar to the format of the Ford Foundation grant file: (1) grant proposal, recommendation and approval letters, (2) correspondence including interim, annual and evaluation reports, and (3) miscellaneous grant materials. Within each of these sections, items are filed in reverse chronological order.
It should be noted that some grant files are missing some of these documents.
Ford Foundation
- Grant Files, 1968-1974; I
  - 68-01 Duke University, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - 68-02 Center for Law and Policy, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - 68-03 University of California, Berkeley, San Francisco Neighborhood Legal Asst. Fdtn., 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - 68-04 University of California, Hastings College of Law, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - 69-01 District of Columbia Consortium, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - 69-01 District of Columbia Consortium, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 69-02 Northwestern University, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - 69-03 University of Utah, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15-19)
  - 69-04 University of South Carolina, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 69-04 University of South Carolina, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
  - 69-05 Harvard University, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
  - 69-06 Rutgers University, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 27-29)
  - 69-07 Arizona State University, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 30-34)
  - 69-08 University of Wisconsin, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
  - 69-08 University of Wisconsin, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 69-09 Oklahoma Bar Association, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
  - 69-10 Yale University Law School, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
  - 69-11 University of Connecticut, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 42-44)
  - 69-12 University of Connecticut, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 45-47)
  - 69-13 University of Mississippi, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 48-49)
  - 69-14 Valparaiso University, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 50-52)
  - 69-15 University of Minnesota, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 53-54)
  - 69-16 National Council on Crime and Delinquency, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 55-57)
  - 69-17 University of Southern California, Western Center on Law and Poverty, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 58-59)
  - 69-18 University of Chicago, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 60-61)
  - 69-19 New York University, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 62-63)
  - 69-20 University of Maine, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 64-65)
  - 69-21 University of California, Berkeley, San Francisco Neighborhood Legal Asst. Ftdn., 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 66-69)
  - 69-21a University of California, Hastings College, San Francisco Neighborhood Legal Asst. Ftdn., 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 70-71)
  - 70-01J Boston University, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 72-73)
  - 70-02J Emory University, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 74-75)
  - 70-03J University of Florida, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 76-78)
  - 70-04J Georgetown University, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 79-80)
  - 70-05J Georgetown University, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 81-82)
  - 70-06J University of Louisville, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 83-85)
  - 70-07J University of South Carolina, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 86-87)
  - 70-08J University of Southern California, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 88-91)
  - 70-09J Southern Methodist University, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 92-93)
  - 70-10J Stanford University, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 94-96)
  - 70-11J Texas Tech University, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 97-98)
  - 70-01 University of California, Los Angeles, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 99-103)
  - 70-02 Case Western Reserve University, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 104-105)
  - 70-03 Columbia University, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 106-107)
  - 70-04 Howard University, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 108-110)
  - 70-05 Marquette University, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 111-112)
  - 70-06 University of Miami, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 113-114)
  - 70-07 New York Law School, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 115-116)
  - 70-08 New York University, 1970-1973 (Box 10, Folder 117-118)
  - 70-08 New York University, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - 70-09 Syracuse University, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 120-122)
  - 70-10 University of Toledo, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 123-125)
  - 70-11 Villanova University, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 126-128)
  - 70-12 Wayne State University, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 129-131)
  - 70-13 Yale University, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 132-133)
  - 70-14 University of Connecticut, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 134-135)
  - 70-15 Northeastern University, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 136-137)
  - 70-16 University of Arizona, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 138-140)
  - 70-17 Boston University, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 141-142)
  - 70-17 Boston University, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - 70-18 S.U.N.Y., Buffalo, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 144-146)
  - 70-19 Catholic University, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 147-148)
  - 70-20 University of Cincinnati, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 149-150)
  - 70-21 Dickinson School of Law, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 151-152)
  - 70-22 Harvard University, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 153-154)
  - 70-23 University of New Mexico, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 155-156)
  - 70-24 Northwestern University, 1970-1975 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - 70-24 Northwestern University, 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - 70-25 University of Oregon, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 159-160)
  - 70-26 University of Puerto Rico, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 161-162)
  - 70-27 St. Louis University, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 163-164)
  - 70-28 University of South Carolina, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 165-167)
  - 70-29 Texas Southern University, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 168-169)
  - 70-30 Washburn University, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 170-174)
  - 70-31 University of Wyoming, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 175-177)
  - 70-32 University of Texas at Austin, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 178-179)
  - 70-33 Rutgers University, 1970-1972 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - 70-33 Rutgers University, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 181)
  - 70-34 Institute of Judicial Administration, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 182-183)
  - 71-01F Yale Law School, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 184-185)
  - 71-02F University of Southern California, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 186-187)
  - 71-03 American University, 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 188-190)
  - 71-04 Boston College, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 191-192)
  - 71-05 University of California, Los Angeles, 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 193-194)
  - 71-06 Capitol University, 1971-1974 (Box 16, Folder 195-196)
  - 71-07 University of Colorado, 1971-1977 (Box 17, Folder 197-198)
  - 71-08 University of Denver, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 199-201)
  - 71-09 University of Detroit, 1971-1974 (Box 17, Folder 202-203)
  - 71-10 Drake University, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 204-205)
  - 71-11 University of Florida, 1971-1977 (Box 17, Folder 206-207)
  - 71-12 Georgetown University, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 208-209)
  - 71-13 Indiana University, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 210-212)
  - 71-14 University of Iowa, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 213-214)
  - 71-15 University of Kansas, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 215-217)
  - 71-16 Louisiana State University, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 218-219)
  - 71-17 Loyola University, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 220-221)
  - 71-18 University of Michigan, 1971-1975 (Box 19, Folder 222-223)
  - 71-19 University of Montana, 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 224-227)
  - 71-20 University of Pennsylvania, 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 228-230)
  - 71-21 Rutgers University, 1971-1973 (Box 19, Folder 231-232)
  - 71-21 Rutgers University, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 233)
  - 71-22 St. Louis University, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 234-235)
  - 71-23 University of Santa Clara, 1971-1976 (Box 20, Folder 236-238)
  - 71-24 University of Southern California, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 239-241)
  - 71-25 University of Tennessee, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 242-243)
  - 71-26 University of Toledo, 1971-1976 (Box 21, Folder 244-247)
  - 71-27 Vanderbilt University, 1971-1973 (Box 21, Folder 248-249)
  - 71-28 West Virginia University, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 250-251)
  - 71-29 Williamette University, 1971-1973 (Box 21, Folder 252-253)
  - 71-30 York University, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 254-255)
  - 71-30 York University, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 256)
  - 71-31 University of Connecticut, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 257-258)
  - 71-32 Harvard University, 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 259-260)
  - 71-33 Ceylon Law College (T&S), 1971 (Box 22, Folder 261-262)
  - 71-34 Columbia University, 1971-1977 (Box 22, Folder 263-264)
  - 71-34b Columbia University, 1971-1977 (Box 22, Folder 265)
  - 72-01J Georgetown University, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 266-267)
  - 72-01F Golden Gate College, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 268-269)
  - 72-02a University of Texas at Austin, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 270-271)
  - 72-03 Boston College, 1972-1976 (Box 22, Folder 272)
  - 72-03 Boston College, 1972-1976 (Box 23, Folder 273-276)
  - 72-04 Cleveland State University, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 277-279)
  - 72-05 Harvard University, 1972-1979 (Box 23, Folder 280-281)
  - 72-05 Harvard University, 1972-1979 (Box 24, Folder 282-284)
  - 72-06 Hofstra University, 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 285-286)
  - 72-07 Lewis and Clark College, 1972-1975 (Box 24, Folder 287-288)
  - 72-08 University of Minnesota, 1972-1975 (Box 24, Folder 289-290)
  - 72-08 University of Minnesota, 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 291)
  - 72-09 University of North Dakota, 1972-1973 (Box 25, Folder 292-294)
  - 72-09a University of Denver, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 295)
  - 72-10 University of San Francisco, 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 296-297)
  - 72-11 Seton Hall University, 1972-1974 (Box 25, Folder 298-300)
  - 72-12 Washburn University, 1972-1974 (Box 25, Folder 301-303)
  - 72-13 Wayne State University, 1972-1974 (Box 25, Folder 304)
  - 72-13 Wayne State University, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 305)
  - 72-14 Yale University, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 306-307)
  - 72-15 Columbia University, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 308-309)
  - 72-16 American Bar Assoc. Fund For Public Education, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 310-311)
  - 72-17 Catholic University, 1972-1976 (Box 26, Folder 312-314)
  - 72-18 Emory University (Materials), 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 315)
  - 72-19 Columbia University, 1972-1975 (Box 26, Folder 316-317)
  - 72-20 University of Costa Rica, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 318)
  - 72-21 Law Development Centre (Kakmpala, Uganda), 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 319)
  - 72-22F University of Texas at Austin, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 320-321)
  - 72-23 International Legal Center (T&S), 1972 (Box 27, Folder 322-323)
  - 73-01 The Institute of Judicial Administration, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 324-325)
  - 73-02 American Bar Association Fund for Public Education, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 326-327)
  - 73-03 University of Pennsylvania, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 328-329)
  - 73-04 Texas Southern University, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 330-331)
  - 73-05 University of Southern California, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 332-333)
  - 73-06 Yale University, 1973-1975 (Box 27, Folder 334-335)
  - 74-01 Capital University, 1974-1976 (Box 27, Folder 336-337)
  - 74-02 Cleveland State University, 1974-1977 (Box 27, Folder 338-339)
  - 74-03 Columbia University, 1974-1976 (Box 27, Folder 340-341)
  - 74-04 Florida State University, 1974-1977 (Box 28, Folder 342-345)
  - 74-05 Georgetown University, 1974-1977 (Box 28, Folder 346-349)
  - 74-06 Harvard University, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 350-351)
  - 74-07 Harvard University, 1974-1976 (Box 28, Folder 352-353)
  - 74-08 Harvard University, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 354-355)
  - 74-09 University of Illinois, 1974-1976 (Box 29, Folder 356-358)
  - 74-10 Loyola University, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 359-361)
  - 74-11 Loyola University, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 362-363)
  - 74-12 University of Missouri, 1974-1976 (Box 29, Folder 364-365)
  - 74-13 National Institute for Trial Advocacy, 1974-1977 (Box 30, Folder 366-368)
  - 74-14 University of New Mexico, 1974-1977 (Box 30, Folder 369-370)
  - 74-15 State University of New York at Buffalo, 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 371-375)
  - 74-16 New York University, 1974-1977 (Box 31, Folder 376-377)
  - 74-17 University of North Dakota, 1974-1976 (Box 31, Folder 378-379)
  - 74-18 Ohio State University, 1974-1977 (Box 31, Folder 380-383)
  - 74-19 University of Oregon, 1974-1976 (Box 31, Folder 384-386)
  - 74-20 University of Pennsylvania, 1974-1976 (Box 31, Folder 387)
  - 74-20 University of Pennsylvania, 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 388)
  - 74-21 University of San Diego, 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 389-390)
  - 74-22 University of San Diego, 1974-1977 (Box 32, Folder 391-392)
  - 74-23 Seton Hall University, 1974-1979 (Box 32, Folder 393-394)
  - 74-24 University of South Dakota, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 395-396)
  - 74-25 University of Southern California, 1974-1978 (Box 32, Folder 397-398)
  - 74-26 Temple University, 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 399-400)
  - 74-27 University of Tennessee, 1974-1978 (Box 33, Folder 401-402)
  - 74-28 Texas Southern University, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 403-404)
  - 74-29 Vanderbilt University, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 405-406)
  - 74-30 Washburn University, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 407-409)
  - 74-31 Washington University, 1974-1978 (Box 33, Folder 410-411)
  - 74-32 University of Wisconsin, 1974-1977 (Box 33, Folder 412)
  - 74-32 University of Wisconsin, 1974-1977 (Box 34, Folder 413-416)
  - 74-33 Yale University, 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 417-418)
  - 74-34 York University, 1974-1978 (Box 34, Folder 419-420)
  - 74-35 Association of American Law Schools, 1974-1977 (Box 34, Folder 421-422)
  - 74-36 Antioch College, 1974-1977 (Box 34, Folder 423)
  - 74-36 Antioch College, 1974-1977 (Box 35, Folder 424-427)
  - 74-37 University of Minnesota, 1974-1976 (Box 35, Folder 428-430)
  - 74-38 University of Michigan, 1974-1977 (Box 35, Folder 431-432)
  - 74-39 American Bar Assoc. Fund for Public Education, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 433-434)
  - 74-40 University of Minnesota, 1974-1976 (Box 36, Folder 435-436)
  - 75-02 Brigham Young University, 1974-1978 (Box 36, Folder 437-438)
  - NI 70-020 LEAA Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 36, Folder 439-441)
  - NI 70-020 LEAA Reports, 1970-1977 (Box 36, Folder 442-443)
  - NI 70-020 LEAA Reports, 1970-1977 (Box 37, Folder 444)
  - NI 70-020 LEAA Expenditures Reports, 1970-1977 (Box 37, Folder 445)
  - NI 70-020 LEAA Miscellaneous, 1970-1977 (Box 37, Folder 446)
- Appendix A: CLEPR Grantees and Grant Number, 1968-1974
  Appendix A: CLEPR Grantees and Grant Number, 1968-1974
  American Bar Association Fund for Public Education 72-16, 73-02, 74-39 American University 71-03 Antioch School of Law 74-36 Arizona State University 69-07 Association of American Law Schools 74-35 Boston College 71-04, 72-03 Boston University 70-01J, 70-17 Brigham Young University 75-02 Capital University 74-01, 71-06 Case Western Reserve University 70-02 Catholic University 70-19, 72-17 Center for Law and Policy 68-02 Ceylon Law College 71-33 Cleveland State University 72-04, 74-02 Columbia University 70-03, 71-34, 71-34B, 72-15, 72-19, 74-03 Dickinson School of Law 70-21 District of Columbia Consortium 69-01 Drake University 71-10 Duke University 68-01 Emory University 70-02J, 72-18 Florida State University 74-04 Georgetown University 70-04J, 70-05J, 71-12, 72-01J, 74-05 Golden Gate College 72-01F Harvard University 69-05, 70-22, 71-32, 72-05, 74-06, 74-07, 74-08 Hofstra University 72-06 Howard University 70-04 Indiana University 71-13 Institute of Judicial Administration 70-34, 73-01 International Legal Center 72-23 Law Development Centre (Kakmpala, Uganda) 72-21 Lewis and Clark College 72-07 Louisiana State University 71-16 Loyola University 71-17, 74-10, 74-11 Marquette University 70-05 National Council on Crime and Delinquency 69-16 National Institute for Trial Advocacy 74-13 New York University 69-19, 70-07, 70-08, 74-16 Northeastern University 70-15 Northwestern University 69-02, 70-24 Ohio State University 74-18 Oklahoma Bar Association 69-09 Rutgers University 69-06, 70-33, 71-21 Seton Hall University 74-23, 72-11 Southern Methodist University 74-23, 72-11 St. Louis University 70-27, 71-22 Stanford University 70-10J State University of New York at Buffalo 70-18, 74-15 Syracuse University 74-26 Temple University 74-26 Texas Southern University 70-29, 73-04, 74-28 Texas Tech University 70-11J University of Arizona 70-16 University of California, Berkeley, San Francisco Neighborhood Legal Asst. Fdtn. 69-21, 68-03, 68-21 University of California, Hastings College, San Francisco Neighborhood Legal Asst. Fdtn. 68-04, 69-21a University of California, Los Angeles 70-01, 71-05 University of Chicago 69-18 University of Cincinnati 70-02 University of Colorado 71-07 University of Connecticut 69-11, 69-12, 70-14, 71-31 University of Costa Rica 72-20 University of Denver 71-08, 72-09a University of Detroit 71-09 University of Florida 70-03J, 71-11 University of Illinois 74-09 University of Iowa 71-14 University of Kansas 71-15 University of Louisville 70-06J University of Maine 69-20 University of Miami 70-06 University of Michigan 71-18, 74-38 University of Minnesota 69-15, 72-08, 74-37, 74-40 University of Mississippi 69-13 University of Missouri 74-12 University of Montana 71-19 University of New Mexico 70-23, 74-14 University of North Dakota 72-09, 74-17 University of Oregon 70-25, 74-19 University of Pennsylvania 71-20, 73-03, 74-20 University of Puerto Rico 70-26 University of San Diego 74-21 University of San Francisco 72-10, 74-22 University of Santa Clara 71-23 University of South Carolina 69-04, 70-07J, 70-28 University of South Dakota 74-24 University of Southern California 70-08J, 71-02, 71-24, 73-05, 73-25 Western Center on Law and Poverty 69-17 University of Tennessee 71-25, 74-27 University of Texas at Austin 70-32, 72-02A, 72-22F University of Toledo 70-10, 71-26 University of Utah 69-03 University of Wisconsin 69-08, 74-32 University of Wyoming 70-31 Valparaiso University 69-14 Vanderbilt University 71-27, 74-27, 74-29 Villanova University 70-11 Washburn University 70-30, 72-12, 74-30 Washington University 74-31 Wayne State University 70-12, 72-13 West Virginia University 71-28 Williamette University 71-29 Yale University 69-10, 70-13, 71-01, 72-14, 73-06, 74-33 York University 71-30, 74-34
- Appendix B: CLEPR Grantees, 1975-1977
  Appendix B: CLEPR Grantees, 1975-1977
  1975 Los Angeles County Bar Association Brigham Young University